Sameer Bindlish (1) Featured

Senior Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, DotNet, .NET, Microsoft C#, ASP. NET, MVC, ADO. NET, WCF, Restful Service, JQuery, JavaScript, Ajax, NHibernate, SQL, WinForm, WPF



Current Designation: Senior Software Developer Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: S&P Global , Gurgaon Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer Industry: Accounting/Finance Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Developer, Software Development, Application

Programming, ASP.NET, MVC, ADO.NET, WCF, JQuery, JavaScript, NHibernate, .Net, DotNet, WPF, SQL Server, C#, Design

Patterns, OOPS, LINQ, Windows Forms, Winforms, Web Services, .NET Framework, Windows Services

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Full stack developer having 10+ years of good experience in developing applications using various technologies and also have good experience in dealing with the multiple onshore as well as offshore development technical team & application users.

Work Experience

S&P Global , Gurgaon as Senior Software Developer Sep 2014 to Till Date

Senior Software Developer (Sep 2017 - Present) Software Developer II (March 2015 - August 2017) Senior Software Engineer (September 2014 - February 2015)

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Private Ltd, as Senior Developer Jan 2014 to Sep 2014

Work responsibilities:

Understanding requirements from BA/PL.

Actively involved in indentifying best practices & latest technologies and helping team in implementing the same.

Coding related to the enhancement and the bug fixes.

Unit testing, assisting in quality testing & production release.

Skills:

Telerik Kendo UI Web JavaScript Library & Kendo UI - MVVM Design Pattern, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS,HTML5, MVC4, C#, .NET 4.0, WCF Restful service ,ADO.NET & SQL Server 2008 T-SQL.

NCR Corporation India Pvt. Ltd, as Software Engineer

Apr 2012 to Jan 2014

RQS Project

Work responsibilities:

Taking requirements from US team & helping team members in requirement understanding & coding. Coding related to the change requests & the production bug fixes. Unit testing, assisting in testing & production release.

Skills:

Knockout Js - MVVM Design Pattern, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS3, HTML5, MVC3, C#, .NET 4.0, WCF, N-Hibernate(one of the ORMs like Entity Framework), LINQ, SQL Server 2008 T-SQL, SSL & msbuild

Reporting Portal

Work responsibilities: Taking requirements from US team Coding complex queries. Unit testing, assisting in testing & production release.

Skills:

SSRS, batch files & SQL Server 2008 T-SQL

Max Bupa Health Insurance Co. Ltd, Delhi as Software Engineer Jul 2011 to Apr 2012

Avis e Solutions, Noida as Associate Developer Jul 2010 to Jun 2011

I worked at client location i.e. Max Bupa Health Insurance Co. Ltd, Delhi

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIU) in 2010

IT Skills

е	Experience	Last Used	Version	Skill Name
				Microsoft C#
				ASP.NET ,MVC 3/4
				WCF Restful Service
				Web Services , JQuery, JavaScript
				Ajax, Knockout Js
				MVVM, JSON, Obout Grid
				RequireJS, HandlebarJS
				ADO.NET
				NHIBERNATE
				Oracle 10g, SQL & PL/SQL
				SQL Server
				T-SQL
				VISUAL STUDIO
				Oracle SQL Developer
				Crystal REPORTS
Month(s)	0 Year(s) 0 M			SVN , TFS & GIT
Month(s)	0 Year(s) 0 M			Windows XP/7/10
				Crystal REPORTS SVN , TFS & GIT

Jenkins

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

Physically Challenged: No